James Wotherspoon

www.jameswotherspoon.com

james.wotherspoon@gmail.com 07803343335

Like a lot of people lockdown made me reassess what career path I wanted to follow, I decided to take the leap and teach myself the skills required for frontend development – I used a variety of sources from Codecademy, books and the plethora of online resources available; Mozilla, blog posts and Stack overflow to name a few. The decision to go for a self-taught approach, turned out to be more challenging than initially thought, however it has given me the ability to solve problems independently. I'm excited to apply the skills I've learnt, in a professional environment and to continue to learn and to improve the quality of my work.

I began by learning Html, CSS and vanilla JavaScript, to build basic websites. I then went on to learn about React, Sass, jQuery and utilizing Apis. Recently I've been learning about the factors to consider for production, such as webpack bundling, cross browser compatibility, and other factors to improve user experience for all. Have a look at some of my work, any feedback would be really appreciated. I hope to hear from you soon.

Education

University of Exeter

(September 2015 - June 2019)

• BSc Biological Sciences with a Study Abroad - University of Helsinki : Class II, Division II

Hitchin Boys' School

(September 2008 - June 2015)

- A Levels:
 - o Biology A
 - o Fine Art A*
 - o Mathematics B
- 10 GCSE's, grade A* B
- Level 1 Certificate in Latin and Sports Leadership

Experience

Sales Executive, StepChange Outsourcing, Hitchin

(July 2020 - March 2021)

• This was a sales-based role speaking to BT customers. The majority of my day was spent on the phone, and I would often have 30 minute to an hour long conversations with customers about their lives and anything in between. I would consistently hit my weekly targets and I was offered the opportunity to move up to the next level of sales executive just before I left.

Recruitment consultant, Vivid Resourcing, London

(February - June 2020)

I was responsible for business development and candidate sourcing specializing in IT
 Infrastructure. The majority of my time was spent on the phone interacting with hiring
 managers and potential candidates. I thoroughly enjoyed speaking to these people, building
 relationships and learning about their work. The fast-paced, target driven environment of G2V
 made it essential for me to develop efficient organizational skills to optimize my time and

achieve the targets expected. I was put on the furlough scheme in mid-April due to the Covid-19 situation.

Host, Surf Safari, Morocco

(October – December 2019)

 While working at Surfsafari Morocco, I provided a high-quality service for the guests, by focusing on communication and organization I provided a personalised rota to ensure a relaxed and enjoyable holiday for the guests.

Team Leader, Mobile Munchies, Hitchin

(July 2015 – August 2019)

A versatile role in maintaining the smooth operation of 3 food vendors at multiple festivals
across the UK. This role has developed by intuition and understanding of the operations of a
small business, as well as testing my customer service skills and judgement.

Research assistant, University of Helsinki, Helsinki

(May - June 2018)

• Assisting a research project studying speciation using hybridizing wood ants as a model species. During this, I worked with a range of scientists from all different backgrounds.

Private Tutoring, Exeter

(January - May 2017)

• Tutoring GSCE level Biology and Maths to several students.

Lab assistant, University of Exeter, Exeter

(November – December 2016)

• Working in a lab assisting a professor with his research.

Teaching Volunteer, Fiji

(June – July 2016)

• Leading English, maths and P.E classes for primary school children in a rural village of Fiji.

Senior Biology Prefect, Hitchin Boys' School

(September 2014 – June 2015)

• As Senior Biology Prefect I played a role in organizing department events.

Shop assistant, Waitrose, Hitchin

(September 2014 – June 2015)

• Working in a variety of roles across the store.

Team leader, Peak assault, Brecon Beacons, Wales

(August 2014)

• Team leader for a 2-day orienteering competition across the Brecon Beacons.

Teaching Volunteer, Kenya

(August 2013)

• Teaching and assisting in a disabled orphanage in Kenya.

Oakley Vault, Letchworth

(February - December 2013)

Achievements and Interests

In 2016 I completed the Amsterdam marathon, and in the process fundraised £1000 for cancer research UK. In 2019 I partook in a charity white-collar boxing match.